<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recipes on Our Cookbook</title><link>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/</link><description>Recent content in Recipes on Our Cookbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 20:13:26 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lemon Raspberry Cheese Cake</title><link>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/lemon-raspberry-cheese-cake/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 20:13:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/lemon-raspberry-cheese-cake/</guid><description>Ingredients Filling 1 cup raw cashews (soaked) 1/2 cup water 1 block (14-16 oz) extra firm regular tofu 1/2 cup freshly squeezed lemon juice (about 3 medium lemons) 2 tbsp quick cooking rolled oats 1 cup vegan cane sugar or raw cane turbinado sugar 1/16 rounded tsp ground turmeric Crust 2 rounded tbsp vegan buttery spread, plus more to coat pan 1 1/2 cups lemon or ginger cookie crumbs Raspberry Swirl 3 rounded tbsp seedless raspberry jam 1/2 tbsp water Instructions Prep Soak cashews in 1/2 cup water.</description></item><item><title>Nacho Cheese Sauce</title><link>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/nacho-cheese-sauce/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 20:13:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/nacho-cheese-sauce/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 cup raw cashews (soaked) 1/2 cup salsa 1 tbsp unsweetened almond milk 2 tbsp water 1 tsp ground cumin 1/2 tsp chili powder 1/2 tsp smoked paprika 1 tsp kosher salt 2 tbsp nutritional yeast 2 tbsp pickled jalapenos + 2 tbsp pickled jalapeno brine Instructions Soak cashews overnight (or in boiling water for 1 hour) Drain soaked cashews and pat dry Add all ingredients to a high-powered blender Blend until thick, creamy, and smooth</description></item><item><title>Taco Meat</title><link>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/taco-meat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 20:13:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/taco-meat/</guid><description>Ingredients 2/3 cup green or brown lentils 8 oz (227g) mushrooms, stems removed and roughly chopped 1/2 small-to-medium onion, very roughly chopped 1/4 cup (30g) walnuts, toasted 1 heaping tbsp ground flax 3 tbsp nutritional yeast 1 tsp kosher salt (plus more to taste) Black pepper to taste 1 tsp smoked paprika 2 tbsp taco seasoning (Optional) 1tsp vegan beef broth seasoning Olive oil (for cooking) Instructions Lentils Add lightly salted water to a sauce pan.</description></item><item><title>Seitan BBQ Brisket</title><link>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/seitan-bbq-brisket/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 11:51:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/seitan-bbq-brisket/</guid><description>Ingredients Wet Mixture 1 cup marsala wine 1/4 cup soy sauce or tamari 1/4 cup maple syrup 2 tbsp sriracha 3 1/2 cup low sodium vegetable stock 1 small can tomato paste (about 1/4 cup) 3+ tbsp olive oil Dry Mixture 2 1/4 cup vital wheat gluten flour (Bob&amp;rsquo;s Red Mill) 3/4 cup chickpea flour (can substitute with oat flour or blended tofu) 2 tbsp chili powder 1 tbsp paprika 1 1/2 tsp cumin 2 tbsp onion powder 2 tbsp garlic powder 1 tbsp salt Instructions Prepare a class baking dish by coating lightly with olive oil.</description></item><item><title>Banana Oat Pancakes</title><link>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/banana-oat-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 20:42:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/banana-oat-pancakes/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 rounded cup bananas (sliced, ~1.5 bananas) 1 cup quick oats 1 tsp baking powder 1 tbsp extra virgin olive oil 2 tbsp maple syrup 3/4 cup + 3 tbsp non-dairy milk 1/4 tsp sea salt Instructions Blend all ingredients until smooth (long enough to get air into batter) Use 1/4 cup batter for each pancake Add non-dairy milk if batter gets too thick Flip pancakes when bubbles start to form around edges</description></item><item><title>Tofu Scramble</title><link>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/tofu-scramble/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 20:13:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/tofu-scramble/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/2 sweet onion (thinly sliced) 1/2 to 2/3 red bell pepper (sliced) 5-6 oz. white mushrooms (sliced) 2/3 to 1 block of extra firm regular tofu 2 tbsp+ extra virgin olive oil separated 2 tsp+ tamari (or soy sauce) separated 1/2 tsp tumeric 1/8 tsp sea salt Instructions Tofu Preparation Squeeze out tofu. You can press the tofu, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t absolutely necessary Crumble tofu into bowl Add 1/2 rounded tsp tumeric Add 1/8 tsp sea salt Add 1 tsp tamari (or soy sauce) Add 1 tbsp extra virgin olive oil Mash tofu until it has the consistency of scrambled eggs Cooking Caramelize onions with 1 tbsp extra virgin olive oil on medium heat (~5 minutes); add 1 tbsp water as needed When onions are golden and translucent, add mushrooms Drizzle tamari (or soy sauce) and extra virgin olive oil over mushrooms Cook down mushrooms for ~5 minutes Add red pepper and 1 tsp of tamari (or soy sauce) Cook for ~3 minutes before adding tofu Mix in tofu Let brown on bottom 1-2 minutes.</description></item></channel></rss>