<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Our Cookbook</title><link>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/</link><description>Recent content on Our Cookbook</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 18:56:51 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DIY Impossible Burger 2.0</title><link>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/diy-impossible-burger-2-0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 18:56:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/diy-impossible-burger-2-0/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 1/2 cups cooked white or brown short grain rice 2 cups TVP Bob&amp;rsquo;s Red Mill 2 cups vegetable broth 2 tbsp coconut oil solid and chilled, not melted (optional) 2 tsp sunflower or other liquid oil (optional) 1/4 cup potato starch flour 2 tsp salt 1 tsp black pepper 1 tsp garlic powder 1 tsp onion powder 1 tsp McCormick&amp;rsquo;s black garlic (optional) 1 tbsp liquid smoke Pinch red pepper flakes 1 tsp A1 steak sauce 2 tsp Better Than Broth vegetable bouillon 2 tbsp finely grated beets Instructions Cook the short grain rice according to package directions and set aside, Place 2 cups TVP in a medium-sized heat-safe bowl.</description></item><item><title>Beyond the Impossible Burger</title><link>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/beyond-the-impossible-burger/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 18:54:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/beyond-the-impossible-burger/</guid><description>Ingredients 12 oz sliced mushrooms, sautéed until browned canned or fresh 1 cup cooked short-grain rice 12 oz tempeh, chopped 1/4 cup quick cook oats, dry 2 tablespoons grated beets 1 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon pepper 1 teaspoon red pepper flakes optional (adds heat) 1 tablespoon nutritional yeast 1 teaspoon garlic powder 1 teaspoon onion powder 1/2 teaspoon liquid smoke 1 tablespoon oil for cooking, if desired Instructions Cook the rice and set aside one cup.</description></item><item><title>Banana Oat Pancakes</title><link>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/banana-oat-pancakes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 20:42:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/banana-oat-pancakes/</guid><description>Ingredients 1 rounded cup bananas (sliced, ~1.5 bananas) 1 cup quick oats 1 tsp baking powder 1 tbsp extra virgin olive oil 2 tbsp maple syrup 3/4 + 3 tbsp non-dairy milk 1/4 tsp sea salt Instructions Blend all ingredients until smooth (long enough to get air into batter) Use 1/4 cup batter for each pancake Add non-dairy milk if batter gets too thick Flip pancakes when bubbles start to form around edges</description></item><item><title>Tofu Scramble</title><link>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/tofu-scramble/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 20:13:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ndonze.github.io/cookbook/recipes/tofu-scramble/</guid><description>Ingredients 1/2 sweet onion (thinly sliced) 1/2 to 2/3 red bell pepper (sliced) 5-6 oz. white mushrooms (sliced) 2/3 to 1 block of extra firm regular tofu 2 tbsp+ extra virgin olive oil separated 2 tsp+ tamari (or soy sauce) separated 1/2 tsp tumeric 1/8 tsp sea salt Instructions Tofu Preparation Squeeze out tofu. You can press the tofu, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t absolutely necessary Crumble tofu into bowl Add 1/2 rounded tsp tumeric Add 1/8 tsp sea salt Add 1 tsp tamari (or soy sauce) Add 1 tbsp extra virgin olive oil Mash tofu until it has the consistency of scrambled eggs Cooking Caramelize onions with 1 tbsp extra virgin olive oil on medium heat (~5 minutes); add 1 tbsp water as needed When onions are golden and translucent, add mushrooms Drizzle tamari (or soy sauce) and extra virgin olive oil over mushrooms Cook down mushrooms for ~5 minutes Add red pepper and 1 tsp of tamari (or soy sauce) Cook for ~3 minutes before adding tofu Mix in tofu Let brown on bottom 1-2 minutes.</description></item></channel></rss>